DEPUTY CHIEF INFORMATION OFFICER (CIO)

Professional Summary

I am currently a Deputy Chief Information Officer for a Federal Agency and a member of the Federal Small Agency CIO Council. I have over 19 years of Information Technology and Information Assurance/Cyber Security technical and managerial experience. I've held positions with the Department of Homeland Security, Booz Allen Hamilton and served with the U.S Army managing IT network operations, and cyber security. I hold several top certifications with ITILv3, MCSE, CISSP and a CIO certificate. I hold a bachelor in computer networking and a master's degree in Information Systems from George Washington University. Skills

- Requirements gathering
- Business process improvement
- Agile methodologies
- · Risk mitigation and management
- Mitigation plan development
- Strategic planning

- Results-oriented
- Collaboration tools
- Project cost planning
- Change management
- Results-oriented
- Team player
- Effective multi-tasker

Work History

Deputy Chief Information Officer (CIO) 04/2013 to Current Applied Research Associates, Inc. – Egg Harbor Township, NJ

- Currently serving as the Deputy Chief Information Officer (DCIO) with responsibility for managing the IT Operations, supervising the agency's IT Specialists and contractors, making recommendations to senior staff with federally mandated reports on IT status and security.
- The project manager and contracting officer for the IT support services contract and any additional contracts the agency enters to provide IT services.
- Serve as an active member and senior representative on the Small Agency Council CIO Committee.
- Major Duties and Responsibilities: Responsible with applying IT principles, concepts, methods, standards and practices in order to identify, recommend, develop, implement and support cost-effective technology solutions, and to provide expert technical advice to the CIO and agency executive management.
- Development of USTDA's Information Technology strategic planning process based upon the mission priorities of the Agency and the CIO, and serves as the lead resource to the CIO in developing the annual operating and capital budgets for USTDA information and technology systems operations consistent with programmatic plans and established financial guidelines.
- Serve as the Senior Information Security Officer for the Agency, performing a wide range of information assurance functions for the Agency such as conduct agency assessment and accreditation and FISMA annual systems auditing requirements.
- Developed and maintain an agency-wide business recovery plan to ensure timely and effective restoration of IT services in the event of a disaster.
- Ensures agency systems meet requirements of Privacy Act and Personally Identifiable Information regulations.
- Negotiate IT acquisition contracts and service level agreements with provider organizations.
- Maintain knowledge of current technology, equipment, prices and terms of agreements to minimize the investment required to meet established service levels.
- Monitor IT systems performance to assure service levels are being met.
- Manage IT support service contract, including administration and oversight of IT functions, including network engineering and administration; desktop engineering and administration; technical support services; remote access and mobility; operational processes; security; and system maintenance.
- Lead all IT efforts related to COOP testing and development.
- Work with COOP manager to complete COOP reporting and annual exercise requirements for the Agency.
- Perform contingency planning and disaster recovery planning and operations.
- Manage team activities, coordinate assignments, communicate project objectives, oversee work performance and progress, resolve problems and issues, and assure that program objectives, deadlines, requirements and priorities are met.
- Acceptance/rejection of contractor supported activities.
- Convey program objectives and clarify subtle distinctions, resolve problems and promote effective working relationships between the IT Team and program staff.
- Provide technical IT advice and assistance to the CIO by maintaining a working knowledge of Information Technology and Communication (ITC) developments within the federal government and by providing research, analysis and advice with respect to ITC investments, maintenance and policies.
- Draft IT policies and standards relating to the acquisition, implementation, and operation of information technology and communication systems and represents USTDA's IT interests with external entities such as government, vendors, researchers, and other organizations.
- Serves as Agency representative to the Federal Small Agency CIO council Monitor and evaluate IT activities and costs needed to meet
 programmatic operational requirements and recommend and coordinate projects related to selection, acquisition, development and
 implementation of major information systems for the Agency.

Senior Cyber Security Analyst 05/2011 to 04/2013 Honeywell â€" Orange , TX

 Provide subject matter expertise in the development and implementation of (Chemical Facility Anti-Terrorist Security) CFATS-related training, policies, processes and procedures, based upon experience and expertise in personnel security, physical security, cyber security,

- information security, and/or industrial security programs.
- Advise managers on new developments and advances in security processes, methods, techniques, systems, and devices.
- Perform vulnerability identification, risk analysis, assessment of evolving threats, information security, physical security, and information technology security, develop and coordinate vulnerability reduction measures; perform protective action planning and implementation; and participate in the development and management of the training programs designed to bring government expertise and experience in protection and response activities to the chemical sector.
- Develop policies, procedures, standards, training and methods for ensuring CFATS compliance, including the areas of preventing identifying
 and protecting information, personnel, property, facilities, operations, or material from unauthorized disclosure, misuse, theft, sabotage, or
 loss.
- Provide advice, guidance and direction to higher-level management, other security specialists and/or subject matter experts throughout the Department, officials of Federal, State and local public safety and law enforcement agencies, and representatives of private sector organizations and contractors on

Chief Warrant Officer Information Technology Management Specialist 05/2009 to 04/2011 Dairy Farmers Of America – Winthrop , MN

- As a recognized technical expert I provided INFOSEC principles and practices.
- Duties included leading a variety of complex project tasks applying knowledge of network protocols, architecture, equipment, services, standards and technology to DOD information security technology challenges that include

IT Manager, Signal Communications Officer S6, Primary Staff Officer 07/2008 to 02/2009 Consolidated Communications $\hat{a} \in TX$

- 157th CSSB Battalion Battalion Communications S6/IT Manager for a forward deployed Combat Support Battalion consisting of three companies and one detachment on six different Forward Operating Bases with over 580 Soldiers.
- Responsible for the health and welfare of 5 Soldiers; perform duty as IT Manager, Primary Staff Officer for Battalion and Acting Company Commander when called upon.
- Manage all frequency allocations and assignments.
- Prepared and conducted of company planning, designing, configuration and installation of network operations centers.
- Responsible to secure all network security, manage and schedule maintenance, and the accountability of the battalion's network and communication's equipment.
- Responsible for designing, developing and implementing unit level signal maintenance and training program; responsible for briefing the Battalion Commander and Staff daily on communication status within the Battalion.

Lead Network Engineer and Information Assurance Security Officer 09/2003 to 07/2008 Rockwell Automation, Inc. $\hat{a} \in \text{``Katy'}$, NY

- Responsible for the managing, overseeing Cisco network devices, Windows 2003 active directory for unclassified and classified networks.
- Provide designs and upgrade recommendations for different level networks.
- Work hand in hand with ISSO for preparation and documentation required for Certification and Accreditation of the client existing network.
- Daily responsibility consisted of and not limited to; Weekly meeting to identify new designs, upgrades, and existing network findings Monitor Network performance and utilization Security Protection Scanning of networks to identify vulnerabilities.
- Work closely with security team to maintain required documents and adhere to security standards Prepared, tested, and deployment of
 mobile network kits for agency critical missions.

Lead Systems Administrator 05/2003 to 09/2003 SkyBitz Inc $\hat{a} \in \text{``Buffalo'}$, STATE Chief Warrant Officer 04/2000 to 04/2011 United States Army Reserves $\hat{a} \in \text{``City'}$, STATE Network Administrator/Analyst 02/1999 to 05/2003 Teleglobe Inc $\hat{a} \in \text{``City'}$, STATE Detachment Commander, Information Systems Specialist 10/1998 to 01/1999 CETECH Inc $\hat{a} \in \text{``City'}$, STATE Network Engineer 08/1996 to 08/1998 Logicon Syscon $\hat{a} \in \text{``City'}$, STATE Network Administrator/Pc Support Technician 04/1993 to 02/1996 United States Army $\hat{a} \in \text{``City'}$, STATE

• Active Duty Assignment, Logistics, New Jersey, Korea.

IT Manager, Lead Engineer Booz Allen Hamilton- DISA ADNET Skyline 3 â€" City, STATE

- Lead Engineering for Windows, UNIX, and network infrastructure engineers designing and deploying enterprise network solutions.
- Responsible for frequent, direct, independent interaction with Government client as the primary focal point for status and issues of technical
 aspects of projects, ability to resolve individual technical issues with peer teams (security engineering, software development), as well as
 coordination and/or cognizance of subordinate's interactions with client.
- Project and technical management of multiple projects to show progress to meet customer expectations on multiple tasks.

Associate Engineer Booz Allen Hamilton- DISA DMZ Skyline 7 â€" City, STATE

- As a Network Engineer for the client my responsibilities consisted of providing technical writing and processes of network systems.
- Design, configure and install Microsoft Windows 2003 Virtual servers to be utilized in a lab environment.
- This live setup, identical to the production network was utilized to thoroughly test networks and server configuration upgrades, security, and configuration modifications.

Associate/Team Manager Booz Allen Hamilton - DISA JTF â€" City, STATE

- As a Lead Network Engineer for the client my responsibilities consist of managing and overseeing the NIPRNET, SIPRNET and over 30 employees, and support over 600 users for the JTF-GNO network.
- My major responsibilities consist of

Education

Master of Science: Computer Information Systems 2014 George Washington University - City, State

Computer Information Systems

• Coursework in Computer Science and Information Technology

Certified Internet Systems Security Professional (CISSP) Certified MCSE 4.0, 2000, 2008, Microsoft Windows 7 Information Technology Infrastructure Library ITIL Foundation v3 Certification <math>2:

Accomplishments

Led the certification and accreditation for a federal agency's unclassified network, managed and oversaw mandated information systems security to a successful highly rated secured certified network.

Successfully led the an upgrade and implementation for a new SAN solution for a new unclassified network

Designed, configured and implemented a new VMWare virtual environment and reduced hardware servers from 20 servers to 1 virtual environment.

Designed and \hat{A} implemented security management solutions to \hat{A} monitor, identified and mitigate \hat{A} network and systems vulnerabilities for a federal network. \hat{A}

Skills

active directory, Agency, auditing, backup, budgets, Cisco 3, Cisco, Citrix, clarify, network systems, Configuration Management, contracts, Council, client, clients, Dell, Dell servers, designing, direction, disaster recovery planning, documentation, executive management, financial, Firewall 5.2, Government, IDS, IIS, Information Security, Information Systems, Information Technology, innovation, interpretation, investments, ITIL, law enforcement, leadership, Logistics, Managing, materials, Meetings, access, MCSE 4.0, exchange, mail, Office, Microsoft Windows 7, Windows, Windows 2000, 2000, Microsoft Windows 2003, Windows NT, enterprise, Network Design and Integration, network engineering, Network Engineer, Network Security, Network, networks, personnel, policies, processes, progress, protocols, reporting, research, risk analysis, risk management, safety, Scanning, server configuration, servers, service level agreements, software development, software installation, strategic planning, supervising, switches, system configuration, system analysis, technical management, technical support, technical writing, training programs, UNIX, upgrades, upgrade, VERITAS Backup, VPN